appleseeds.com 2013-10-27

# Privacy and Security | Appleseeds

Please note that the privacy and security policies and data collection processes for these Orchard Brands family of related companies may differ from this Privacy and Security Policy published for Appleseed's, The Tog Shop, WinterSilks, LinenSource, Blair, Old Pueblo Traders, Bedford Fair, and Willow Ridge. Please refer to the website for each of these related companies for their particular privacy and security policy detailing how that affiliated company handles your privacy concerns and personal information. 

* * *

**What information do we collect?**

We use a variety of methods to gather information to help ensure that your shopping experience is as efficient and accommodating as possible. We may obtain personal information about you from various sources, including through your communications with us. We also collect certain information by automated means, using technologies such as cookies and pixel tags. 

You may choose to provide personal information to us in a number of ways, such as when you: 

  * Request a catalog or information about our products and services
  * Visit our website, or outlet locations
  * Create an online shopping account
  * Purchase, return, or exchange a product by phone, mail or online
  * Contact our call center or customer service desk
  * Participate in a promotion, contest or survey
  * Provide us with comments or suggestions

The types of information we may collect, in order to serve you better, include: 

  * Contact information such as name, mailing address, phone number, and email address
  * Personal information such as billing address and credit card information, when provided
  * Demographic and preference information such as product purchase history
  * Information you provide about other people, such as a gift recipient

When you set up an online shopping account at our web site, if applicable, we may also request a password to allow you secure access.

We may also supplement the information listed above with anonymous Site traffic information that's collected automatically when you visit our Site, plus with information acquired from our joint marketing partners, from third parties, and from our affiliated companies.

* * *

**How do we use your information?**

You deserve the fastest, safest and most enjoyable shopping experience possible. To give you just that, we may use information that you provide to us in the following manner:

  * To assist you in customer service communications
  * To administer "My Account" information, online forms, and other site features
  * To enable you to check out and complete your purchases, and to fill and ship your orders
  * To send you special announcements or promotional information about new products or services and upcoming events, and to allow our affiliated companies and our other trusted third party partners to do the same
  * To send you printed catalogs in the mail
  * As necessary, to share your information with trusted third-party companies that provide support services to us or with which we partner to provide services, including special programs, offers and discounts
  * To help improve our Site
  * Where we consider it necessary to protect your legal rights, our legal rights, or the legal rights of third parties, or where required by law.

More details of the ways in which we may use your information are set out below.

**In-store Shopping**

When you visit one of our stores or outlet locations, you can shop anonymously when you pay with cash. However, we may keep a history of your purchases if you use a credit card or debit card. We collect this information in order to process your orders and to better assist you, and all such information will be treated in compliance with this privacy policy. 

If you want to return or exchange purchased merchandise, we may ask you for personal identification information such as the credit card used for the purchase or a picture ID to help prevent fraud.

**Emails**

We may use your e-mail address to notify you about the status of your order (if you have placed one), provide customer service information, or answer your questions and requests. We may also occasionally send you our e-mail updates, sales notifications, or other promotional information about our products and services or about the products and services of our affiliated companies or trusted third party partners in which you may be interested. We may also share your e-mail address with our affiliated companies to enable them to send you emails directly regarding their products and services, sales and other promotions.

**Telephone Contact**

If you provide us with your phone number, you may receive telephone contact from us for customer service communications, such as to ask you about your order, if you have placed one. If you call our customer service toll-free number, we may ask you for personal identification information, depending on the nature of your request, to better assist you with your requests and questions. We may retain this information to help meet your future needs. 

We may occasionally use your phone number to contact you with updates, sales notifications, or other promotional information about our products and services or those of our affiliated companies or trusted third party partners in which you may be interested. We may also make your personal information available to our affiliated companies and our other trusted third party partners to enable them to contact you directly with their promotional information, such as information about their products and services, sales and other promotions.

**Contests, Promotions, or Surveys**

If you participate in a contest, promotion, sweepstakes offering, or survey (whether online, over the phone, by mail, or at one of our outlet stores), we may use your personal information to manage your entry in such promotion, to notify you if you are a winner, or to fulfill promotional obligations. At the time of your entry or registration for a specific promotion, survey, contest, or sweepstakes, we will provide you with the rules governing such promotion, survey, contest, or sweepstakes.

**Authorized Third Parties**

We partner with certain third parties who provide services to us, such as managing visitor/customer information, managing our marketing and promotions activities, and conducting other activities of the kind described elsewhere in this privacy policy on our behalf. In such cases, we may disclose your personal information to such service providers. We do not authorize any of these service providers to make any use of your information other than for our benefit. 

We may also partner with third party organizations to provide special programs, offers and discounts to members of those organizations, in which case we may disclose to that organization information we collect about you, such as your name, your membership number with that organization, your contact details, and information about your purchases with us. We may also, from time to time, partner with third parties to offer you membership in programs, such as discount programs, run by them, or products and services offered by them; if you elect to participate in such programs or to purchase such products and services, we may disclose your personal information, including your credit card information (if applicable), to enable such third parties to enroll you in their programs or provide those products and services, and to bill you for their services.1 

In addition, to provide you with other marketing information or third party promotions that may be of interest to you, we may disclose your personal information to our affiliated companies and our other trusted third party partners, as set out in this privacy policy.

**Catalogs and Mailings**

We may use your name and postal address to occasionally send you our printed catalogs, magalogs, valpaks or other syndicated mailings, as well as materials regarding offerings of our affiliated companies and our other trusted third party partners. We may also make your name, postal address and transactional information available to our affiliated companies and our other trusted third party partners so that you may receive mailings directly from them about products and services that may be of interest to you.

**Financial Products**

We may offer, now or in the future, financial products to preferred customers (such as credit cards). As a result, we may share your personal information with certain authorized third parties to provide you with tailored information about their special offers and services relating to such financial products.

**By Law**

In certain instances, we may disclose your personal information when we have reason to believe that it is necessary to identify or contact you in relation to, or bring legal action to protect, your legal rights, the legal rights of us and/or of our affiliated companies, or the legal rights of others. We may also disclose your personal information when we believe it is required by law.

**Sale of Business**

In the event that the Orchard Brands Company, any of its affiliated companies, or any part of any of them, is sold, or some or all of their assets are acquired, customer information may be among the transferred assets, and may therefore be used by the third party acquirer.

**Customer Service**

If you provide us with your phone number, you may receive telephone contact from us for customer service communications, such as to ask you about your order. 

If you call our customer service toll-free number, we may ask you personal identifying information, depending on the nature of your request, to better assist you with your requests and questions. We may retain this information to help meet your future needs.

**Catalogs**

We may use your name and postal address to occasionally send you printed catalogs from Appleseed's. We may also share such information, as described herein, with our affiliated-companies or to other reputable direct marketing companies who may have offers of interest to you.

**Emails**

We may use your e-mail address to notify you about the status of your order, provide customer service information or to answer your questions and requests. We may also occasionally send you our Email updates, sales notifications, or other promotional information about our products and services. We will not sell or rent your e-mail address to outside marketing companies. 

You will also be automatically eligible to and may receive similar promotional information via e-mail from our affiliated companies and brands regarding their special announcements such as information about that brand's products and services, sales and other promotions. Please note that any use of personal information by an affiliated company will be governed by that entity's privacy policy. If you want to change how information is used on that company's website, you must do so directly with that company.

**Contests, Promotions or Surveys**

If you participate in a contest, promotion, sweepstakes offering or survey (whether via on-line, over the phone or at one of our outlet stores), we may use your personal information to manage your entry in such promotion, to notify you if you are a winner, or to fulfill promotional obligations. At the time of your entry or registration for a specific promotion, survey, contest, or sweepstakes, we will provide you with the rules governing such promotion, contest or survey.

**Authorized Third Parties**

To provide you with an optimal shopping experience, we partner with certain third parties [to manage our customer information, to fulfill promotions, or to communicate with our customers. In such cases, we may disclose your personal information to such outside companies. We do not authorize any of these service providers to make any use of your information other than for our benefit. 

To provide you with other marketing information or third party promotions that may be of interest to you, we may disclose your name and postal address to reputable third parties but, but not your e-mail address or other information. 

Such third parties may have websites with separate privacy and data collection practices, and we recommend that you carefully review them. If you would like to change how information is used on that third party website, you must do so directly with that third party.

**Affiliate-Company Catalogs**

If you order a product or request a catalog from us, we may make your name, postal address and transactional information available to companies within our family of affiliated companies so that you may receive future catalog offerings about products and services that may be of interest to you.

**By Law**

In certain instances, we may disclose your personally identifiable information when we have reason to believe that it is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action to protect your rights, the rights of Appleseed's, or others. We may also disclose your personally identifiable information when we believe it is required by law.

**Sale of Business**

In the unlikely event that Appleseed's is sold, or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information may be one of the transferred assets, and may therefore be used by a third party acquirer in accordance.

**Information we collect by automated means and how we use it**  
To improve our websites and to make your online experience more enjoyable, when you visit our websites we collect certain information by automated means, using cookies, pixel tags, and other technologies.

Cookies, Web Server Logs and Pixel Tags  
A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a Web server and stored on your computer's hard drive when you visit our websites. We use cookies to tell us who you are, tailor our products and services to suit your personal interests, estimate the number of visitors to our websites, track visits to pages within our websites, process your order, track your status in our promotions, contests and sweepstakes, and/or analyze our customers' visiting patterns. Cookies do not contain information such as name or credit card information. Most browsers are preset to accept cookies and are used to make online visits easier and faster for you. Cookies are not required for you to browse our websites. Please note, however, that without cookies you will not be able to shop or place an order on our websites. In such cases, to place orders, please call us at 1-888-430-5711.

In conjunction with obtaining information through cookies, our web servers may log details such as your operating system type, browser type, domain, and other system settings, as well as the language your system uses and the country and time zone in which your device is located. The web server logs also may record information such as the address of the web page that linked you to our site and the IP address of the device you use to connect to the Internet.

To control which web servers collect this information, we may place ?pixel tags? (also called ?web beacons? or ?clear gifs?), which are tiny graphic images on our websites, to help us gather knowledge about how you use our websites.

Third Party Web Analytics Services  
We may use third party web analytics services on our websites, such as Google Analytics. The service providers that administer these services use technologies such as cookies, web server logs and web beacons to help us analyze how visitors use the site. The information collected through these means (including IP address) is disclosed to these service providers, who use the information to evaluate use of the website. To disable the Google Analytics cookie and any other third party web analytics service provider cookies, some browsers indicate when a cookie is being sent and allow you to decline cookies on a case-by-case basis.

Targeted Advertising  
We also may contract with third-party advertising networks that collect IP addresses and other information through the use of cookies, web server logs and web beacons on our websites and e-mails and on third-party websites and e-mails. They use this information to provide advertisements about products and services tailored to your interests (including for companies not affiliated with us). You may see these advertisements on our websites and other websites. This process also helps us manage and track the effectiveness of our marketing efforts.

How we may use information collected by automated means  
We may use the information we collect through automated means on our websites for market research, data analytics and system administration purposes, such as to determine whether you've visited us before or are new to the site, and for compliance with our legal obligations, policies and procedures, including compliance with relevant industry standards. We may combine the information we collect through automated means with other information we have collected from you. This information may be used to improve our websites, to personalize your online experience, to focus our communications with you to items of the most interest to you, to determine the effectiveness of our advertising, and for other internal business purposes to improve your shopping experience with us. We also may use the information in other ways for which specific notice is provided at the time of collection.

**How do we share your information?**  
We do not sell or otherwise disclose personal information we collect about you, except as described here. We may share your personal information with:

Orchard Brands Affiliated Companies  
To provide you with other marketing information or promotions that may be of interest to you, we may disclose your personal information to our other Orchard Brands affiliated companies. We may also make your name, postal address and transactional information available to our Orchard Brands affiliated companies so that you may receive mailings directly from them about products and services that may be of interest to you.

Authorized Third Party Service Providers  
Certain service providers perform services on our behalf based on our instructions. We do not authorize these service providers to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or comply with legal requirements. Examples of these service providers include entities that process credit card payments, fulfill orders, provide web hosting, manage our marketing and promotions activities, 

Other Trusted Third Parties  
We may, from time to time, partner with third parties to provide you with special offers. If you elect to take advantage of such an offer, you will be eligible to transact with such third party partner only if you provide them your personal information directly. We may make your name, postal address and transactional information available to certain trusted third party partners so that you may receive mailings directly from them about products and services that may be of interest to you. Also, some of our Facebook apps may share information collected through those apps with your Facebook friends or other Facebook users.

By Law  
In certain instances, we may disclose information about you (1) if we are required to do so by law or legal process, (2) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials, or (3) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss, or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual fraudulent or illegal activity.

Sale of Business  
We also reserve the right to transfer personal information we have about you in the event that Orchard Brands Corporation, or any of its subsidiary companies or any part of any of them implicating the Appleseed's and/or The Tog Shop business(es), sells or transfers all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use personal information you have provided to us in a manner that is consistent with our Privacy Policy. Following such a sale or transfer, you may contact the entity to which we transferred your personal information with any inquiries concerning the processing of that information.

* * *

**How can you control the use of your information?**

We want you to be in control of your information, and we want to communicate with you only if you want to hear from us.

**Account Management**

You can contact us at any time to review, change or delete certain personal information. Simply call our customer service specialists at 1-888-430-5711.

**E-mails**

If you do not want to receive our electronic newsletter or promotional e-mails, you may unsubscribe at any time by clicking on "unsubscribe" at the bottom of any of our promotional e-mails.

**Catalogs**

If you do not wish to receive our printed catalog, please contact our customer service specialists at 1-888-430-5711. When you give us your name and address as it appears on the mailing label, we will remove your contact information from our mailing list. Please allow several weeks for the catalogs to stop, as catalog delivery is scheduled well in advance.

**Telephone Contact**

If you do not wish to receive telephone calls from us regarding our sales notifications or promotions, please contact our customer service specialists at 1-888-430-5711. Please note that we may continue to contact you by telephone for customer service communications (such as in relation to orders that you have previously placed with us).

**Facebook App Opt-Out**  
To remove or delete our apps from your Facebook account, follow the [instructions ](https://www.facebook.com/help/?faq=170585223002660) provided by the Facebook Help Center. **Sharing Information with Third Parties**

If you would rather that we did not share your personal information with our affiliated companies or our third party partners for their direct marketing purposes, please send your full name, address and customer number to our mailing address listed at the end of this privacy policy. Please note that even if you opt out of having your information shared with third parties in this way, we may still disclose your information to third parties in other circumstances as described in this privacy policy, for example, where required to enable our third party service providers to provide services to us, and where required by law.

Please also note that where we have previously disclosed personal information to an affiliated company or third party partner prior to your opting out, that company's use of your information will be governed by its privacy policy. If you want to change how information is used by an affiliate company or third party (for example, by opting-out of receiving emails or telephone communications from that company), you must contact that company or party directly. We cannot alter or remove your information from any of our affiliated companies' or third party partners' databases.

* * *

**How do we safeguard your information?**

Protecting the safety of your personal information is important to us. Where we maintain an online store, we use a variety of technical, administrative and physical safeguards so that you can enjoy your shopping experience without having to worry about the loss of, misuse of, or unauthorized access to your information.

**Secure Shopping**

Where our Site permits you to enter credit card or other billing information, we use industry-standard encryption technologies to encrypt that information while it is being transmitted to our Site. In addition, we make commercially acceptable efforts to stay up to date with best practices regarding the protection of information in connection with transactions occurring over the internet.

**Firewalls**

We protect all personal information stored in our computer systems, including information about your orders, behind a network security system called a "firewall." We only permit our authorized staff and authorized third party service providers to access our computer systems, and then only for the purposes described in this privacy policy.

**Phone Orders**

Some versions of popular web browsers and some firewalls do not permit communication through secure servers like the ones we use to process orders. If your web browser cannot support this level of security, you will not be able to order products through our Site or those of our affiliated companies. If so, you may place orders by calling us toll-free at 1-888-430-5711.

We follow industry practices to protect your personal information from unauthorized access, but no data transmission over Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. We cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us over the Internet. Also, please note that e-mail is not encrypted and is not considered a secure means of transmitting credit card numbers.

* * *

**What technologies do we use to enhance your shopping experience?**

To improve our Site and to make your online experience more enjoyable, we may collect anonymous information about all visitors to our Site, through the use of cookies, image tags, and other technologies.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a Web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. We use cookies to tell us who you are, tailor our products and services to suit your personal interests, estimate the number of visitors to our Site, track visits to and sales at the stores referenced on our Site, process your order, track your status in our promotions, contests and sweepstakes, and/or analyze our customers' visiting patterns. Cookies do not contain any personal identification information (such as name or credit card information). Most browsers are preset to accept cookies and are used to make online visits easier and faster for you. Cookies are not required for you to browse our Site, however they are required for you to shop on our Site or to place an order. If you set your browser to refuse cookies, purchasing is not possible at our Site. In such cases, to place orders, please call us at 1-888-430-5711.

**Image Tags**

We may at times work with a third-party company to help us gather knowledge about how you use this Site through the use of image tags, so that we may constantly improve your online experience. In such cases, the third-party company's only role is to help us conduct our business and deliver the most relevant products and services. They are not permitted to use your personal identification information for their own purposes.

**Third Party Links**

Our Site may include links that take you to other web sites for outside business partners, vendors and advertisers. These web sites have separate privacy and data collection practices. We have no control over such web sites, and are not responsible or liable for the privacy practices or information-gathering practices of other entities or web sites.

We have also contracted with third parties to monitor certain pages of our Site for the purpose of reporting Site traffic, and/or other advertising statistics. Where authorized by us, these third parties may use cookies and/or other monitoring technologies to compile anonymous statistics about our Site visitors. No personal identification information is transferred to these third parties. For more information about how data is collected and used, please see their privacy policies <http://www.dotomi.com/privacy.html>

* * *

**Children's Privacy**

This Site and the web sites of our family of companies are not directed towards children; we do not knowingly collect any personal information from children under 13 years of age.

* * *

**California Privacy Rights**

In certain circumstances, California law entitles California residents to request us to provide, free of charge and no more than once per calendar year, a list of the categories of the resident's personal information disclosed by us to third parties for such third parties' direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year, together with the names and addresses of all such third parties and a description of such third parties' businesses, if not already reasonably apparent from the third parties' names. If you are a California resident and would like to receive such information, please contact us using the mailing address at the end of this privacy policy.

* * *

**Changes to the Privacy Statement**

By using this Site, you consent to the collection and use of your personal information as described herein. We reserve the right to change, modify or amend this policy from time to time. If our privacy policy changes, we will notify you by publishing the new policy on our Site together with its effective date. Once effective, the new policy will apply to all personal information we currently hold, whether collected before or after the new policy's effective date. We encourage you to periodically review our current privacy policy.

* * *

**How to Contact Us**

Our customers come first. If you have any concerns or questions, you can contact us by:

  * Sending us an E-mail:[customerservice@appleseeds.com](mailto:customerservice@appleseeds.com)
  * Writing to us at Appleseed's 30 Tozer Road, Beverly, MA 01915
  * Calling us toll-free at 1-888-430-5711

* * *

**Conflict in Terms**

It is our goal to make our privacy practices easy to understand. We have created this easy-to-read privacy policy with that goal in mind. Some browsers utilize privacy enhancing technology to translate our privacy policy into a computer readable format. The technology then requires that the computer format be translated back into human readable format for you to read. This translation back into human readable format is often referred to as a "Policy Summary"; it is possible that through these translations, the Policy Summary may unintentionally end up being inconsistent with the privacy policy upon which it is based. It might fail to address an issue or it might address an issue not raised in our privacy policy. For this reason, you should rely on our privacy policy as the most accurate and definitive description of our practices.

* * *

**Patent Disclosure**

One or more patents may apply to this Site or those of our affiliated brands, including without limitation, U.S. Patent #5,528,490; #5,761,649; and #6,029,142.

  1. We also use a third-party service provider to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet and sometimes on our Site. They may collect anonymous information about your visits to our Site, and your interaction with our products and services. They may also use information about your visits to our Site and other websites to target advertisements for goods and services. This anonymous information is collected through the use of a pixel tag, which is industry standard technology used by most major websites. No personally identifiable information is collected or used in this process. They do not know the name, phone number, address, email address, or any personally identifying information about the user. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this anonymous information used by our third party service provider, please click here <http://www.dotomi.com/privacy.html>

You can also read more about online marketing practices and the technologies that support them by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative"s website at [Network Advertising](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

  2. We also use VeriSignTM as our SSL provider as an added measure for your protection. You may want to check your internet settings to make sure your browser is in compliance with industry-standard encryption technology.
